Fight evil... With evil.
Solomon Kane is a adventure, fantasy, action film directed by MJ Bassett.
A nomadic 16th century warrior, condemned to hell for his brutal past, seeks redemption by renouncing violence, but
finds some things are worth burning for as he fights to free a young Puritan woman from the grip of evil.
Solomon Kane, played by James Purefoy.
William Crowthorn, played by Pete Postlethwaite.
Katherine Crowthorn, played by Alice Krige.
Father Michael, played by Mackenzie Crook.
Josiah Kane, played by Max von Sydow.
Malachi, played by Jason Flemyng.
Solomon Kane is a 2009 sword and sorcery film based on the pulp magazine
character of the same name created in 1928 by Robert E.
Written and directed by M.
Bassett, the film stars James Purefoy in the title role.
Despite obtaining the rights in 1997, filming did not begin until January 2008.
The film is an original story for the Kane character and
was intended to be the first of a trilogy.
The plot follows a redemption story for Kane, from the end of his life as a privateer, through the salvation of his soul
by rescuing a Puritan girl and the beginning of his life as the Puritan avenger of the source material.
It was produced by a consortium of French, Czech, and British
companies and mostly filmed in the Czech Republic.
The film was first shown at the 2009 Toronto International Film Festival.
It went on general release in France, Spain, and the UK over
the end of 2009 and the beginning of 2010.
It has a Rotten Tomatoes rating of 67%.
The screenplay was novelised by award-winning fantasy author Ramsey Campbell.
The film explores themes of mercenary, trap, murder, puritan, sorcerer.
The tone is dark.